the farm is the cia's uh clandestine
training facility it's
in it's
in Virginia it's in
Virginia and uh it's where almost all of
your operational training is going to
take place everything from
counterterrorist driving to all of your
weapons
qualifications to a born where they they
train you how to jump out of a plane and
how to use a parachute um then they they
do the the nuts and bolts um how to
recruit spies to steal Secrets exercises
you know that there are other facilities
too uh things like
um bomb
training um specialized stuff out in the
desert out west
but most of it 80% of it is at the farm
so you go they've got they've got dorms
I guess you could call them dorms um and
uh classrooms and tracks and shooting
ranges and anything you need I mean the
thing is
like thousands of
Acres so anything you need to do you can
do with the
farm what was your
favorite thing that you did
there you know everybody loved shooting
the
most uh I it it was the driving for
me it was the driving for me my God I
got so much out of that class I still
use it I still use what I learned all
these years later um we did things like
the the course was colloquially known as
crash and bang so you crash cars and you
shoot guns and you know and then you do
cool stuff like one one night we did
well we did we did night shooting a lot
but we we did like rocket launchers like
where else are you g to do rocket
launchers grenade launchers and blow
[__] up and blow cars up and that was so
much fun but for me the driving was
better because they put you in these
scenarios
where I gotta be careful I don't go into
too much detail but
you got a blindfold on okay you're in
the driver's seat and you're driving
like a mile an hour with a blindfold on
and they're steering for you and they
say okay I'm going to take the blindfold
off and you have two seconds to
react okay so they take the blindfold
off and just as they take the blindfold
off you notice in your peripheral vision
there's a guy with an AK-47 who's trying
to open your door and then there are two
guys in front of you you and they're
they have their cars in a V but which
way is it is it a v like this or is it a
v like
this so if it's a v like this you got to
gun it and crash right through if it's a
v like this you're just going to wedge
yourself and they're going to blow your
brains out so you have to put it in
reverse before this guy shoots you with
a
paintball um and you got to go reverse
you know 50 60 70 m an hour they teach
you how to hit the brakes neutral spin
around drive without ever coming to a
stop and you take off and they they call
it getting off the
X so you do this three times and you
know you [__] it up one time you're dead
that's it you're
dead
so I was good at that
that my response time was very quick it
was under a
second and and it's little stuff that
that people forget that get you killed
you forget to lock your door always
always always lock the door
always I mean even now the the risk of
being carjacked at a red light or stop
sign or something is is is
real that lock may buy you an extra
second or two seconds which is really
all you need to get off the dime so I
was good at that and then they marry the
two guns and
cars so you go through these very
elaborate complicated
exercises where they they have a device
on all the cars where they can kill the
engine remotely so you're just driving
down the track mining your own business
and your car dies and and so
you you drive over you're you you drift
over to the side now we're using all
live ammo here by the way um and so
really yeah you pull over and you hear a
gunshot now they haven't shot directly
at you they shot in the air so you hear
The Gunshot so you have to you have to
crouch down so that they can't get you
through the you have live ammo they
don't uh they can't get through the
windshield and then you put it in park
you crawl across the the seat get out
the passenger side lay on the ground
you've got your gun and you have to look
to see where the shooting's coming from
well the the shooting is coming from
these robots that they have they're
they're automated and they've got little
Targets on them black and white rings so
the thing is shooting at you it's
shooting blanks and you're on the ground
and you have to you know bang bang and
then you hear a shot over there bang
bang but sometimes you can't quite get
it cu the robots turn to the side or the
the targets turn to the side so on your
belly you have to go to the back of the
car and then get it from that angle well
there was one there was one point that I
just couldn't get a clear shot what it
was across the way there was a van and
the the sliding door of the van had
opened and the robot was in the van and
the robot's firing at me and I just
can't get a clean shot so I pop up and I
shoot out my own Windows they give you
these beater Ford Tauruses I shoot out
my own windows and I go bang bang and I
get
it
so they they sound this air horn which
means you know weapons down so you
holster your
weapon and the guy the instructor comes
out he goes well you passed
but damn it
karako you just cost me
$900 in broken
windshields I said I couldn't get a
clean shot I'm sorry we did this one
exercise it was at night we drew straws
to see who would go first and I went
first so all you know in this scenario
is you are in a flea bag hotel in in El
Salvador good luck
so it's just a a table and a
chair
and and it it looks like a flea bag
Hotel I mean it's like a Hollywood set I
mean they they this is real life they
make it look like it really is going to
look in real life so you're sitting
there you're not really sure what to
expect and there's a knock on the door
and you say who is it and then the door
opens and it's these two guys and one of
them is holding a a a vacuum cleaner and
they're saying housekeeping seor
housekeeping and I go I don't need
housekeeping I don't need
housekeeping and then the guy the second
guy behind him pulls out a gun and goes
bang bang he shoots me with two paint
pellets I go [__] I said I never saw
that
coming and one of the instructors
says if you're in a [__] hole Motel in a
[__] hole country and two people just
walk into your room kill
them and he's like don't tell anybody
else what the exercise is so I go back
out to the van we're all sitting in the
van waiting our turn and I got these two
paint things here and one of them just
says
[__] and I said yeah I can't talk about
it all eight of us failed all eight of
us failed
that was such an important lesson I
never ever forgot it and so
anytime I felt threatened or anytime I
felt you know what in this situation I'm
in right now I can see a point 10
seconds down the road where I might feel
threatened I would draw my weapon just
in case it happened twice just in case
then we went through something you've
I'm sure Seen On TV it's a shooting
Gallery so you've got your you've got
your gun out and the instructor's right
behind you and he's got his hand on your
shoulder
and a guy pops up in a window and he's
got a a machine gun and you go bang bang
and he plops down and then a woman pops
up holding a baby over here and you know
you have to make sure not to shoot her
if you shoot her you
fail I have chills thinking about it it
taken me back I haven't talked about
this in decades and so um crazy as it
sounds I got 100% I was like a freaking
Marksman and the funny thing is on the
very first day of of the weapons
training um like I say there were eight
of us and the instructor said anybody
here not own a gun and I I raised my
hand and I kind of looked around and I
was the only guy that had his hand up he
goes you don't own a gun and I said
truth be told I've never actually
touched a real gun and he goes oh my God
okay we're going to have to start from
the very
beginning and I ended up testing first
in the class to the point where one of
the instructors said you should give
some thought to competitive shooting wow
and so I did and I ended up like winning
trophies in ski I just had a knack for
it I had a very steady hand and um it
served me well wow mhm that's so
interesting about the scenarios they set
up like you said at the motel and with
the blindfold is it a matter of like how
fast can you process information and
make decisions with the available
information is that kind of what they're
T that's exactly what it is and not just
in the shooting but in the driving too
you know you might have seen on on one
of these oldtime cop shows like atam 12
for example i' I've seen this on atam 12
um you're you're speeding toward three
red lights right there there are three
lanes you're in the middle Lane red red
red and one second before you get to the
red lights one of them turns green and
you have to Swerve as fast as you can to
the green light and if you go through
the lane with the red light you fail and
if you fail you can't go
overseas and so it was the same thing
with the driving man I aced the
counterterrorism driving I AC it to the
point
where um they came up to me afterwards
and said when are you leaving for for
overseas and I said oh I still have two
more months and they said we want you to
take the advanced driving class it's out
in the Nevada desert he said that's real
counterterrorism driving and so I went
out there and it was like driving over
sand dunes and what do you do if you get
stuck in the sand and it was it was good
stuff I learned a
lot
what's up guys thank you so much for
taking the time to watch the interview
um as you could probably tell this is a
brand new channel so if you got anything
out of this at all please like the video
leave me a comment tell me what you
thought tell me who you'd like to see on
the show um I see every like I read
every comment and I appreciate all of it
especially in the beginning because as
you know that kind of support goes a
long way on these platforms so most
importantly I have some awesome guests
coming up in the future for interviews
um so please subscribe to the channel so
you don't miss any of them but again
thank you for your time appreciate the
support and hope to see you again soon